Caleb Brewster Papers, 1755-1976 Ms 33
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Caleb Brewster Papers, 1755-1976
Ms 33
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.75 Linear feet 1 box
Box Oversize Manuscripts Box 1--Item A
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of one box and three oversize items. Folders A through C hold deeds; Folder D probate papers; Folder E maps and military papers; Folder F financial and legal papers; Folder G legal papers and correspondence; Folder H an address by William Brewster Minuse; and Folder I a family Bible which belonged to Caleb Brewster. The oversize items are maps which are stored in the Fairfield Historical Society map case. For further details, see the Table of Contents.
Biographical/Historical note
Caleb Brewster, born at Setuaket, New York, in 1747, settled in Black Rock after many seafaring years. He was notable for his role as a Revolutionary War spy, commanding a fleet of whale boats from Black Rock Harbor. After the war he married Anna Lewis and became a large land owner and captain of a revenue cutter for the district of New York. He died in Black Rock in 1827. For further information, see Folder I in this collection.
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Brewster, Anna Lewis; Brewster, Caleb, 1747-1827; Minuse, William Brewster; Bible records.; Correspondence.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Fairfield(Conn.)--History--Maps.; Probate records.; Writs--Connecticut.
- Deeds, 1783-1787, Series A; 14 items
  - John Squire, III and Caleb Brewster from Samuel Smedley and Jonathan Sturges, 1784
  - John Squire, III and Caleb Brewster from Samuel Smedley, 1784
  - Robert Brush and Caleb Brewster from Israel Bibbin (collector), 1786
  - Robert Brush and Caleb Brewster from Richard Hubbell (collector), 1786
  - Caleb Brewster from James Hoyt, 1787; 2 items
- Deeds, 1792-1796, Series B; 13 items
  - Caleb Brewster from Robert Brush, 1792; 3 items
  - Caleb Brewster from Robert Wilson, 1792
  - Caleb Brewster from Samuel Squire, 1792
  - Caleb Brewster from Ebeneezer Silliman, 1793
  - Anna Brewster from Lothrop Lewis, 1793
  - Lothrop Lewis from Caleb Brewster, 1793
  - Anna Brewster from Caleb Brewster, 1794
  - Caleb Brewster from Nicol Floyd, 1794
  - Anna Brewster from Sam and Ellen Squire, 1796
  - Anna Brewster from Samuel Burr, et al., 1796
  - Caleb Brewster from Jonathan Sturges, 1796
- Deeds, 1798-1818, Series C; 15 items
  - Anna Brewster from Thaddeus Benedict, 1798
  - Anna Brewster from Sarah Malcom, et al., 1798
  - Caleb Brewster from Daniel Tolles, 1802
  - Caleb Brewster from John Wheeler, 1802
  - Anna Brewster from James Knapp, 1803
  - Gershom Burr from Caleb Brewster, 1803
  - Gershom Burr from Caleb Brewster, 1803
  - Anna Brewster from William Wheeler, 1804
  - Anna Brewster from William Wheeler, 1806
  - Anna Brewster from Samuel Read, 1804
  - Caleb and Anna Brewster from Lothrop Lewis, 1809
  - Caleb Brewster to Jonathan L. Brewster, 1815
  - Sturges Brewster from Caleb and Anna Brewster, 1815
  - Sturges Brewster from Caleb Brewster, 1818
  - Anna Brewster from Sturges Brewster, 1818
  - Empty deed packet, n. d.
- Probate Papers, 1755-1870, Series D; 7 items
  - Caleb Brewster will, 1827
  - Clarina Brewster will, 1849
  - Jonathan Lewis will, 1792
  - Court appointments for Clarina Brewster's will, 1870
  - Jonathan Bulkley real estate distribution, 1796
  - Obediah Wheeler real estate distribution, 1755
- Maps and Military Papers, 1778-1799, Series E; 9 items
  - Ezra Wheeler map, n. d.
  - Hulls and Lords lot map, 1793
  - Captain Hoyt map, n. d.
  - Caleb Brewster homestead map, 1799
  - Caleb Brewster homestead map, n. d.
  - Misc. map, n. d.
  - Military certificate for Caleb Brewster re: provisions, 1783
  - Bill to Caleb Brewster from Jonathan Lewis re: rations, 1778-1782
- Financial and Legal Papers, 1761-1799, Series F; 34 items
  - Bills receipted to Caleb Brewster, 1787-1801; 4 items
  - Miscellaneous bills, 1790-1794; 3 items
  - Caleb Brewster promissory note, 1787-1788; 3 items
  - James Hoyt promissory note, 1786
  - Ezra Wheeler promissory note, 1783-1802; 4 items
  - Orders and notes of Caleb Brewster, 1787-1799; 5 items
  - Property appraisals, 1787-1799; 9 items
  - Caleb Brewster farm lease to Ezra Wheeler, 1788
  - Caleb Brewster farm lease to Grudus Bulson, 1793
  - Caleb Brewster farm lease to Peter Marks, 1793
  - Caleb Brewster wharf right payment, 1795
  - Ichabod Wheeler wharf permission, 1761
- Legal Papers and Correspondence, 1794-1811, Series G; 16 items
  - Subpoena, Caleb Brewster vs. Ezra Wheeler, 1802
  - Bill to Caleb Brewster for Wheeler case, 1806
  - Subpoena, David Allen et al., 1800
  - Petitions of Caleb Brewster, 1794-1795; 5 items
  - Summons, Ebeneezer Jessup et al., 1799
  - Writ, Caleb Brewster vs. Thomas Nash, 1790
  - Writ, Caleb Brewster vs. David Matbie, 1806
  - Joshua Davis testimony, 1780, n.d.; 2 items
  - Certificate, Daniel Tolles vs. Ezra Wheeler, 1802
  - Invitation to Captain Brewster from Governor Tomkins, N. Y., 1811
  - Letter, Brewster Hackley from Lewis Brewster, n.d.
  - Letter, David Gilster from Caleb Brewster (photocopy), 1809
- Address by William Brewster Minuse re: Caleb Brewster, 1976, Series H
- Caleb Brewster family Bible with family records (photocopy), 1793, Series I
- Oversize Items: Maps, 1783-1806, 3 items
  - Land swap between William Wheeler and Caleb Brewster, 1806
  - Land belonging to heirs of Jonathan Lewis, 1793
  - Land belonging to Ebeneezer Wakeman, 1783